A racing second hand, a shooting comet,
،عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
a pop-up doll, and broken ceramic!
دمية آلية الخروج وخزف محطّم
Mystery-solving logic is helpful against people's dry hearts!
المنطق المفكّك للغموض مفيد في مواجهة قلوب الناس الجافّة
Heiji Hattori looks poised to discover Conan's real identity today!
هويّة كونان الحقيقية تحت خطر !اكتشاف هاتّوري هيجي لها
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and there's no outwitting his logic!
!وباستنتاجات لا مُضاهٍ لها
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The old man, Ran, and I went on a trip for Sherlock Holmes fans.
ذهبتُ مع العمّ وران في رحلة لمُعجبي شارلوك هولمز
However, the car of Kanaya-san,
...لكنّ سيّارة كانايا-سان
this trip's director and owner of the Mycroft Lodge,
"مُشرف الرحلة ومالك نُزل "ماي كروفت
fell over a cliff and exploded!
سقطت من جرف وانفجرت
Moreover, having been isolated from the outside world,
وأيضاً بعد عزلنا عن العالم الخارجي
we shut ourselves in the lodge to prevent any further casualties,
أغلقنا على أنفسنا في النُزل لمنع وقوع المزيد من الضحايا
but Ayako-san, who claimed to know the identity of the killer,
لكنّ أياكو-سان التي ادّعت اكتشافها لهويّة القاتل
died in an explosion in the garage!
!ماتت في انفجار في المرآب
Was the owner responsible?
أكان المالك هو الفاعل؟
Or was it one of the five other guests
أم أحد الضيوف الخمسة الآخرين
excluding us three and Heiji Hattori?
باستثنائنا الثلاثة وهاتّوري هيجي؟
Suddenly, Fujisawa-san was attacked by someone with an ice pick!
في خضّم الأحداث، تعرّض فوجيساوا-سان للهجوم بكسّارة ثلج
The Holmes Freak Murder Case (Part 2)
(جريمة قتل مهووس هولمز (الجزء الثاني
Who would do such a thing?!
!من قد يفعل هذا؟
It was the owner.
كان المالك
He faked his death during the first incident,
زيّف موته في الحادثة الأولى
hid somewhere inside this lodge,
واختبأ في مكان ما في النزل
burned Ayako-san to death in the garage,
حرق أياكو-سان في المرآب
then attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick
ثمّ هاجم فوجيساوا-سان بكسّارة ثلج
and escaped out that window!
وهرب بعد تحطيم تلك النافذة
Damn it! Why would the owner want to kill me?!
تبّاً! لمَ يريد المالك قتلي؟
I even helped him with the book he published!
!ساعدتُه في الكتاب الذي نشره حتّى
Book?
الكتاب؟
A Holmes book he published last year with his own money.
كتاب عن هولمز نشره العام الفائت بأمواله
I believe the title was "The Disparagement of Irene Adler."
"أظنّ العنوان كان "سخرية آيرين أدلر
Irene Adler?
آيرين أدلر؟
Alright, Ran! We're going after the owner!
!حسناً يا ران، سنلاحق المالك
Right!
أجل
Forget about it. There's no point.
لا جدوى، توقّف
You'd never find the killer by looking out there!
لن تجد القاتل بالبحث خارجاً أبداً
What do you know?!
ماذا؟
Take a closer look at this chair.
أمعن النظر لهذا الكرسيّ
See how it's unnaturally placed at the narrow end?
ألا ترى أنّه موضوع بشكل غير طبيعيّ في الطرف الضيّق؟
It's proof that the killer quickly pushed it under
إنّه دليل على أنّ القاتل أدخله في عجلة
after breaking the window.
بعد تحطيمه النافذة
He's right! There are pieces of glass stuck in it!
!هذا صحيح! توجد شظايا زجاج به
The killer must have used this chair!
!لا بدّ أن الفاعل استعمل هذا الكرسيّ
But that only proves the killer used the chair to--
...لكنّ ذلك يثبت استعمال القاتل للكرسيّ وحسب
You idiot! Who would bother putting a chair back
أحمق! من قد يهتمّ بإعادة كرسيّ
after smashing a window to escape through it?
بعد تحطيمه نافذةً للهرب؟
The killer probably held the chair with bare hands
أمسك الفاعل الكرسيّ بيديه العاريتين غالباً
when they broke the window!
عندما حطّم النافذة
It was too dark to remove the fingerprints,
كان الظلام حالكاً فلا يستطيع مسح البصمات
so the killer put the chair back under the table--
لذا أرجع الفاعل الكرسيّ تحت الطاولة كيلا نلاحظ
After the lights came back on?
بعد عودة الكهرباء؟
Wait, we were the only ones in the room then...
...لحظة، كنّا الوحيدين في الغرفة وقتها
That's right.
أجل
Now do you see that the owner didn't do it,
أفهمتم الآن أنّ المالك لم يكن الفاعل
and that the killer is in this very room?!
!وأنّ الفاعل في الغرفة بيننا؟
Maid. You said a fuse had blown
أيّتها الخادمة، قلتِ أنّ مِصهراً قد احترق
when the lights went out, correct?
عندما انقطعت الكهرباء، أليس كذلك؟
Yes! When I tried to plug in the coffee maker,
أجل، عندما حاولتُ إدخال قابس صانعة القهوة
it suddenly sparked!
!صدرت شرارة
It was this outlet!
انظروا، كان هذا المقبس
There was a thin wire wrapped around the plug
كان هناك سلك رفيع مربوط حول القابس
so that it would cause a short if someone were to plug it in.
كي يحدث انقطاع إذا أدخله أحد
But where did the killer get this wire?
لكن من أين حصل الفاعل على السلك؟
I bet it was this!
من هذا غالباً
The wire attached to the top of this coffee pack!
السلك المربوط بأعلى حزمة القهوة هذه
The width and length do match perfectly...
السماكة والطول متطابقان حقاً
Who opened the packs?
من فتح الحزمة؟
Kawatsu-san and Togano-san...
كاواتسو-سان وتوغانو-سان
Now it's clear.
اتّضح الأمر الآن
You're the killer, Kawatsu-san!
!أنتَ الفاعل يا كاواتسو-سان
Hold on, now!
!ا-انتظر قليلاً
There were three other people in the kitchen besides me--
كان هناك ثلاثة أشخاص ...غيري في المطبخ وقتها
You moron!
!أحمق
All three of those people have alibis for the first incident!
!يمتلك أولئك الثلاثة حجج غياب للحادثة الأولى
You most likely took a wire off a pack when no one was looking,
أخذت السلك من الحزمة عندما لم ينتبه لك أحد غالباً
wrapped it around the plug, and then returned to the living room
وربطته حول القابس ثم عدت لغرفة المعيشة
to wait for the lights to go out!
وانتظرت انقطاع الكهرباء
Then, in the darkness,
وعندها، في الظلام
you attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick
هاجمت فوجيساوا-سان بكسّارة ثلج
that you carried in here with some ice--
جلبتها هنا مع قطع ثلج
using the flame from his lighter to find him!
واستعملت الشعلة من قدّاحته لتحديد موقعه
However, some unexpected obstacles caused you to fail.
لكن ظهرت عقبات غير متوقعة ففشلت
Isn't that right?
أليس ذلك صحيحاً؟
Yeah, but something's not quite right.
أجل، يبدو ذلك... لكن هنا أمرٌ ما ليس في محلّه
Right, boy?
صحيح يا فتى؟
Yeah.
أجل
The third incident in which Fujisawa-san was attacked
الحادثة الثالثة التي تعرّض فيها فوجيساوا-سان للهجوم
is different than the first two
تختلف عن الحادثتين السابقتين
in that the culprit plainly left evidence behind.
من ناحية ترك الفاعل دليلاً وراءه
Perhaps this third incident wasn't part of the killer's plan?
لعلّ الحادثة الثالثة لم تكن ضمن حسابات القاتل؟
Conan-kun...
...كونان-كن
But I'm just a kid, so what would I know?
لكنّي مجرد طفل، فما الذي أعرفه؟
Don't pay any attention to him!
!لا تهتموا له
He just loves to play detective!
!يحب لعب لعبة المتحرّي فقط
Come over here.
تعال هنا
There's something really strange about this kid!
هناك أمرٌ غريب بهذا الصبيّ
He isn't playing detective! He's really analyzing!
لا يلعب لعبة المتحرّي، إنّه يحلل بدقّة
His voice and body are different, but he's almost just like Kudo!
صوته وجسده مختلفان، لكنّه يشبه كودو
Kudo?!
كودو؟
Yeah! When Kudo showed up during that previous incident,
صحيح، عندما ظهر كودو في القضيّة السابقة
that kid disappeared somewhere!
اختفى هذا الصبيّ
And then when Kudo disappeared, he just popped up again...
وعندما اختفى كودو، ظهر مُجدداً
Could he really be?!
أيمكن أنّه... هو؟
But isn't it strange, Detective?
لكن أليس الأمر غريباً حضرة المتحرّي؟
If Kawatsu-san really is the killer,
إن كان كاواتسو-سان القاتل حقّاً
how did he set the garage on fire during the second incident?
كيف أضرم النار في المرآب في الحادثة الثانية؟
And during the first incident,
،أيضاً في الحادثة الأولى
the owner's car sped up before it went over the cliff!
ارتفعت سرعة سيّارة المالك قبل سقوطها من الجرف
That's right!
!صـ-صحيح
Yeah.
أجل
I've got almost all of the second incident solved,
حللتُ معظم القضيّة الثانية
but the first incident makes no sense...
لكنّ الحادثة الأولى غير مفهومة
Eh? You know how they set the garage on fire?!
ماذا؟ عرفت كيف نشب الحريق في المرآب؟
Well, yeah...
...أجل
At any rate, what I don't understand about the first incident
بأيّ حال، ما لا أفهمه في الحادثة الأولى
are the following four points.
:هو الأشياء الأربعة التالية
Why we didn't see the owner for almost an entire day...
لمَ لم نرَ المالك ليوم كامل تقريباً؟
Why the car suddenly sped up...
وارتفاع سرعة السيّارة المُفاجئ
The odd sound coming from inside the car
والصوت الغريب الصادر من داخلها
and the blanket on the dashboard...
بالإضافة للمُلاءة على مقصورتها
And then one more mystery appeared when we came here.
واللغز الإضافيّ الذي ظهر عندما أتينا هنا
The owner was holding the steering wheel tightly.
كان المالك ممسكاً بعجلة القيادة بإحكام
The car was on a bumpy road, but his body never slumped.
كانت السيّارة على طريق وعر لكن جسده لم يتزحزح أبداً
That means by the time he was placed in the car,
هذا يعني أنّه عندما وُضع في السيّارة
he was long dead and rigor mortis had set in!
كان قد قُتل قبل فترة وتصلّبت جثته
Rigor mortis?!
تـ-تصلّب الجثة؟
A body usually begins to stiffen thirty minutes to two hours after death,
يبدأ الجسد البشريّ بالتصلّب بعد نصف ساعة إلى ساعتين بعد الموت غالباً
and nine to twelve hours later, the body becomes completely stiff.
وبعد 9 إلى 12 ساعة، يتصلّب الجسد كاملاً
Thirty hours after that, under the best circumstances,
،ثلاثون ساعة بعدها، في أفضل الظروف
the body loosens up again and approximately seventy hours later
تلين الجثّة مُجدداً، وبعد 70 ساعة تقريباً
it's back to normal.
تعود لحالتها الطبيعية
If we assume the owner was completely stiff
إذا افترضنا أنّ المالك كان متصلّباً تماماً
when he was placed in the car at 3:30 a.m.,
عندما وُضع في السيّارة عند الثالثة والنصف صباحاً
then he was killed between 3:30 and 5:30 p.m. the previous day.
فيعني أنّه قُتل بين الثالثة والنصف إلى الخامسة والنصف مساء اليوم السابق
In other words, sometime before dinner,
...أي قبل العشاء، لكن
but what I don't understand
ما لا أفهمه هو لمَ وُضِع المالك
is why they had to put him in the car so early...
...في السيّارة باكراً هكذا
Maybe to make it look like a suicide?
ليوهم الآخرين أنه انتحر ربما
My guess is that they killed the owner before dinner,
لعلّ الفاعل قتل المالك قبل العشاء
put him in the car, had him sit with his hands on the wheel,
وأجلسه في السيّارة، ثبّت يديه على عجلة القيادة
waited for him to stiffen, then went to the garage after dinner
وانتظر تصلّبه، ثم ذهب للمرآب بعد العشاء
and sent the car on its way.
وشغّل السيارة
In other words,
ما يعني
the killer was one of you who left after dinner!
أنّ القاتل أحد من غادروا بعد العشاء، بينكم أنتم
Then why did the car speed up?
لمَ ارتفعت سرعة السيّارة إذاً؟
A dead person couldn't possibly have done that...
...لا يمكن أنّ ميتاً قام بذلك
A dead person?!
ميت؟
Could the killer's trick be--
...أيمكن أنّ حيلة الفاعل
If so, then only that person could've done it,
في تلك الحالة، لا يمكن أن يكون سوى ذاك الشخص
but there's still no proof!
لكن لا يزال ينقصنا دليل
Wait a minute!
...لحظة
She did say that Ayako-san was loitering in the hall in the afternoon...
قالتْ أن أياكو-سان كانت تتسكّع عند الرواق ظهيرة اليوم
If she had actually seen something in that person's room...
...لو رأت شيئاً في غرفة ذاك الشخص وقتها
That's it!
!هكذا إذاً
Now I see!
!عرفت
I know the killer's identity!
!هويّة المجرم
Yes, the killer is you!
!أجل، القاتل أنت
Fortuneteller Maria Toda-san!
!يا قارئة الطالع تودا ماريا-سان
You must have used hypnosis to make the owner drive the car!
لا بدّ أنّك استعملتِ التنويم المغناطيسيّ !لجعل المالك يقود السيّارة
Give me a break.
يا للحماقة
I can't wait to use a sleeping dart on him...
...كم أتمنّى استعمال الإبرة المخدّرة
But it's all over if he catches me during my explanation.
لكن ستكون مشكلةً إن كشفني أثناء التحليل
Say! What would happen to the rigor mortis
أخبرني، ماذا يحصل لتصلّب الجثة
if the temperature went up?
إذا ارتفعت الحرارة؟
Would it start sooner?
هل يبدأ بصورة أسرع؟
If so, then you know who did it, huh?
في تلك الحالة، تعرف من الفاعل، صحيح؟
I haven't the slightest idea. I'm pretty dumb, you see.
لا أملك أدنى فكرة، فأنا مغفل
Darn it!
!تبّاً
He knows all right, he's just trying to make me explain it!
!يعرف، لكنّه يحاول جعلي أشرح
Alright, in that case!
حسناً، في تلك الحالة
I'll just be going to the bathroom now...
سأذهب للحمّام
Oh. Then I will, too...
...سأذهب أنا أيضاً
Huh? Where'd he go?
ماذا؟ أين اختفى؟
Will you get serious?!
!هلّا توقفت؟
I'm a fortuneteller, not a magician!
!أنا قارئة طالع! لست ساحرة
That's enough of this farce, old man.
أوقف هذه المهزلة أيّها الرجل المُسن
What?
ماذا؟
I just figured out who the killer is, too!
اكتشفتُ هويّة القاتل...قطعياً أيضاً
You did?
قطعياً؟
That's right.
صحيح
The person behind all three incidents at this lodge... was you!
...الشخص وراء الحوادث الثلاث في هذا النُزل
That's right.
صحيح
The person behind all three incidents at this lodge...
الشخص وراء الحوادث الثلاث ...في هذا النُزل
...was you!
!كان أنت
Eh? Me?!
ماذا؟! أنا؟
No!
!كلا
The man in a cold sweat behind you...
...الرجل الذي يتصبب عرقاً وراءك
...you, Togano-san!
!توغانو-سان، أنت
Wait!
!ا-انتظر
I was here in the living room hours before the car even took off!
كنتُ في غرفة المعيشة لعدّة ساعات !قبل تحرّك سيارة المالك
And when Ayako was killed, I was with everyone else!
!وعندما قُتلت أياكو، كنت معكم
He's right, you moron!
!صحيح يا ساذج
Oh, man! I hope he didn't wake up!
تبّاً! هل أفاق؟
Stop that, Dad!
!توقف يا أبي
Don't you mock me with your fancy Kansai dialect!
!لا تسخر منّي بلكنة كانساي الغريبة هذه
And besides, you were with us too when the car started moving!
!في الأصل، كنتَ معنا عندما تحرّكت سيّارة المالك
How could Togano-san possibly have started the car?!
!كيف استطاع توغانو-سان تحريكها؟
You're right, it certainly appears impossible.
معك حق، يبدو ذلك مستحيلاً
But if he were to utilize the rigor mortis
لكن إذا استغلّ تصلب الجثّة
and a certain function of the car, it would become possible.
ووظيفة ما في السيّارة، سيصبح ذلك في نطاق المعقول
The trick goes like this.
هكذا نفّذ الحيلة
The culprit killed the owner almost exactly one day ago,
قتل الفاعل المالك قبل يوم تماماً
sat him in the car seat, and stuck his foot on the brake.
وأجلسه في مقعد السيّارة، ثم ثبّت قدمه على دواسة المكابح
Rigor mortis would occur half a day later,
سيقع تصلّب الجثّة نصف يوم بعدها
and the brakes would have kept the car motionless
ولم تكن المكابح لتسمح للسيّارة بالحركة
even if the engine was running and in drive.
حتّى لو كانت السيّارة تعمل وناقل الحركة في وضعية القيادة
Before dinner last night, the killer opened the garage
قبل العشاء البارحة، فتح القاتل المرآب
and then waited in the living room for the foot on the brake to loosen up
ثمّ انتظر في غرفة المعيشة ارتخاء القدم على دوّاسة المكابح
and cause the car to start moving...
...فتتحرّك السيارة
You fool!
!أحمق
Rigor mortis doesn't go away
لا يزول تصلّب الجثّة
until at least forty hours after death!
!إلا بعد 40 ساعة بعد الموت على الأقل
You even said so yourself-
...قلتَ ذلك بنفسك
What if the outside temperature increases?
ماذا لو ارتفعت الحرارة الخارجية؟
If the temperature around the body was about 95 degrees Fahrenheit,
إن كانت الحرارة حول الجثّة تُقارب 35 درجة مئوية
the rigor mortis and rate of loosening up would speed up,
سترتفع سرعة التصلّب كما الارتخاء
so it would start to go away after only twenty-four to thirty hours.
فيزول التصلّب بعد 24 إلى 30 ساعة فحسب
It was after 10:00 p.m. two nights ago that the owner disappeared.
اختفى المالك بعد العاشرة ليلاً قبل ليلتين
If he had been killed shortly afterward...
...إذا كان قد قُتل بعدها فوراً
The car started moving approximately twenty-nine hours later
بدأت السيّارة بالتحرّك بعد قرابة 29 ساعة
--before 3:30 this morning--
قبل الثالثة والنصف صباح اليوم
which was just about the right time.
أي في التوقيت المناسب
The hissing sound we heard inside the car
الصوت الشبيه بهسيس الرياح من السيّارة
wasn't the air conditioner-- it was the heater!
!لم يكن جهاز التبريد، بل المدفأة
Had it been the AC,
لو كان جهاز التبريد
water drops would have fallen by the front tires.
لسقطت قطرات ماء عند الإطارات الأمامية
So that's why you were checking around the tire tracks?
لذا كنت تتفقد أثرها؟
That's right.
أجل
Naturally, there were no water marks to be found.
لم تكن هناك أيّ آثار ماء بالطبع
But that trick would be easy to see through
لكن يمكن كشف حيلة كهذه بسهولة
by checking the body...
عبر فحص الجثّة
That's why the killer sent the owner over the cliff in the car!
لذا أسقطها القاتل مع السيّارة من الجرف
To make the body unrecoverable
لجعل استرجاعها مستحيلاً
so we couldn't check the state of rigor mortis!
!بحيث لا نستطيع التحقّق من حالة التصلّب
So why did the car speed up?
كيف ارتفعت سرعة السيّارة إذاً؟
That was probably because his foot slipped off the brake pedal
كان ذلك بسبب انزلاق قدمه عن دوّاسة المكابح غالباً
as the car bumped around.
بعدما دخلت السيّارة الطريق الوعر
And the blanket on the dashboard
والهدف من المُلاءة على المقصورة
was there to conceal the heater indicator
كان إخفاء مؤشّر المدفأة
from people who got near the car!
عمن قد يقتربون من السيّارة
I see!
فهمت
So by witnessing the car with someone else in the room...
لذا بمشاهدة حركة السيّارة ...مع أشخاص آخرين في الغرفة
...they would have an airtight alibi!
!ستحصل على حجّة غياب متقنة
So the reason Togano-san kept Ayako-san in the living room
سبب إبقاء توغانو-سان لأياكو-سان في غرفة المعيشة آنذاك
was because he wanted someone who would witness the car with him?
كان لأنّه يريد أن يشاهد أحد السيّارة معه؟
Precisely.
تماماً
And the only person who could have done such a thing
والشخص الوحيد الذي كان بمقدوره فعل ذلك هو من اصطحبها هنا
was Togano-san!
!أنت يا توغانو-سان
Interesting.
مُسلٍّ
Your theory almost sounds like it's straight out of a novel.
تحليلك كما لو انبثق من رواية
It's too bad you have no evidence to prove it.
لكن من المؤسف أنّ لا دليل لديك لإثباته
And as I've said before, when the fire erupted in the garage,
،قلتُ سابقاً أيضاً، عندما اشتعل الحريق في المرآب
I was in here with everyone else.
كنتُ في الغرفة معكم
No matter how you look at it, there's no way
...مهما نظرتم للأمر
I could have set the fire exactly when Ayako happened to go in there.
من شبه المستحيل أن أضرم الحريق لحظة دخول أياكو المرآب تحديداً
No, but it would still be easy enough...
صحيح، لكن توجد طريقة يسيرة
All you had to do was tell her
كلّ ما كان عليك هو إخبارها
that the first-edition Holmes book was hidden beneath the back seat
أنّ نسخة الطبعة الأولى من رواية هولمز مخبأة تحت المقعد الخلفيّ
of the car in the garage!
!للسيّارة في المرآب
The first-edition book? What's that have to do with anything?
نسخة الطبعة الأولى؟ وما علاقة ذلك؟
Have you forgotten?
أنسيت؟
At that time, the car in the garage was drained of its gasoline
كان البنزين يتسرّب من السيارة في المرآب آنذاك
and its battery removed!
والبطارية نُزعت
the back seat would have been pitch black.
،لكن مع عدم عمل مصابيح السيّارة كان المقعد الخلفيّ مظلماً تماماً
What would you have done?
ما كنتَ لتفعل؟
If it were pitch dark, I'd have to use a lighter or something...
لو كان المكان مظلماً، كنتُ لأستعمل ...قدّاحة أو ما شابه
That's it! A lighter!
!هكذا إذاً! قدّاحة
Ayako-san used a lighter to look for the book!
استعملت أياكو-سان قدّاحة للبحث عن الكتاب
The flame ignited the gasoline that had leaked from the car!
أشعلت نارها البنزين الذي تسرّب من السيارة
So she was the one who started the fire?!
كانت هي من أشعل الحريق إذاً؟
But she was an important witness from the first incident!
!لكنّها شاهدة مهمة في الحادثة الأولى
There were four other witnesses besides her!
كان يوجد هناك أربعة شهود غيرها
There was no need to keep her alive...
لم يكن بحاجةٍ لإبقائها حيّة
But aren't Ayako-san and Togano-san lovers?
لكن أليست أياكو--سان وتوغانو-سان على علاقة؟
Why would he do that?
لمَ قد يفعل ذلك؟
Because she figured out his rigor mortis trick
لأنّها اكتشفت حيلة تصلّب الجثّة
and found evidence that he was the one responsible!
ووجدت دليلاً يدينه
You all remember.
جميعكم تذكرون
Ayako-san declared she knew who the killer was.
أعلنت أياكو-سان أنّها عرفت القاتل
Hearing that, Togano-san grew flustered
هلع توغانو-سان بعد سماعه ذلك
and pretended to follow her to the bathroom.
وتظاهر باللحاق بها للحمّام
He then told her about the first-edition book
ثمّ أخبرها عن نسخة الطبعة الأولى
and lured her into the trap in the garage!
واستدرجها لفخّ المرآب
Now that you mention it,
...بالمناسبة، كان توغانو-سان
Togano-san was the only one alone with her...
هو الوحيد معها آنذاك
So that's why she changed her attitude after leaving the bathroom!
!لذا غيّرت سلوكها بعد مغادرة الحمّام فجأةً
But he certainly was clever to come up with that garage trick...
لكن من العجيب أنّ حيلة المرآب خطرت له حينذاك
No. That trap had been prepared in advance for a certain person...
كلا، كان قد جهّز تلك الحيلة لشخص آخر سلفاً
The killer lucked out because Ayako-san had a lighter,
لم يحالف الحظّ القاتل لأنّ أياكو-سان كانت تحمل قدّاحة
just as that other person would have had!
مثلما كان يملك ذاك الشخص
Yes. The trap in the garage was really meant to kill Fujisawa-san!
أجل، كان الهدف من فخّ المرآب !هو قتل فوجيساوا-سان في الأساس
What?!
!ماذا؟
That card that was stuck in your door...
البطاقة التي كانت عالقة في بابك
The killer intended to lure you into the garage and murder you!
نوى القاتل أن يستدرجك للمرآب ويقتلك
But things didn't go according to plan
لكن لم تمض الأمور وفق خطّته
and the garage trap wound up killing Ayako-san.
وقتل فخّ المرآب أياكو-سان
He quickly devised a plan to cause a blackout
فكّر سريعاً بخطّة انقطاع كهرباء
by fiddling with the outlet
عبر العبث بمقبس
and then attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick!
ثمّ هاجم فوجيساوا-سان بكسّارة ثلج
I see. So that's why there was so much evidence
هكذا إذاً، لذا كانت هناك أدلّة كثيرة
after the third incident...
بعد الحادثة الثالثة
Togano-san was in the kitchen at the time--
كان توغانو-سان في المطبخ آنذاك
he could've very easily fiddled with it!
فأمكنه تجهيز حيلته بكلّ سهولة
In other words, the only person
أي أنّ الشخص الوحيد
who could've pulled off all three incidents...
الذي كان بإمكانه ارتكاب كلّ الحوادث الثلاث
...was Togano-san!
كان أنت فحسب يا توغانو-سان
Then show us your proof!
!فلترني دليلاً إذاً
If you're going to make such accusations, then surely you have proof?
إذا كنت سترميني بهذه الاتّهامات، فيجدر أنّ لديك دليل
Oh? You mean you didn't know?
ماذا؟ لم تعرف؟
Ayako-san saw a certain something in your room
رأت أياكو-سان شيئاً في غرفتك
yesterday afternoon!
ظهيرة الأمس
It doesn't matter what she saw! She can't talk now--
...لا يهم أيّ ما رأته، فلا تستطيع الكلام الآن
Question ♪1.
السؤال 1
"Which hand does Holmes write with?"
"بأيّ يد يكتب هولمز؟"
Question ♪2.
السؤال 2
"What is the name of Dr. Watson's wife?"
"ما اسم زوجة الدكتور واتسون؟"
What is this?!
!ما هذا؟
Oh, my. Have you forgotten?
ماذا؟ أنسيت؟
Didn't you take the Holmes Cult Test of 1000 Questions too?
ألم تحلّ أسئلة اختبار طائفة هولمز الألف بدورك؟
Question ♪241.
السؤال 241
"What did Holmes' letter written in the 'Dancing Men' code
ما نصّت رسالة هولمز المكتوبة" "بشفرة (الرجال الراقصين) المرسلة للقاتل؟
Oh, I remember that question very well...
...أذكر ذاك السؤال جيّداً
The answer is, "Come here at once!"
"كانت الإجابة "تعال هنا فوراً
That question wasn't on the test...
لم يكن ذاك السؤال ضمن الاختبار
There was only that one question about "The Dancing Men"!
...السؤال الوحيد المتعلّق بالرجال الراقصين كان
"Write down the entire 'Dancing Men' code as it appeared!"
(اكتب الشفرة الكاملة من (مغامرة الرجال الراقصين" "كما ظهرت تماماً
That's right.
صحيح
That question was so hard it would be impossible to forget.
كان ذلك صعباً جدّاً بحيث يستحيل نسيانه
Isn't it a little strange that you don't remember it?
أليس غريباً عدم تذكرك له؟
I was just-
...كـ-كنتُ فحسب
The reason Ayako-san went to your room
سبب ذهاب أياكو-سان لغرفتك
was to copy your test answers!
!هو نسخ إجابات الاختبار
But you weren't in your room.
لكنّك لم تكن في غرفتك
You had probably gone to the garage
كنت قد ذهبت للمرآب للتحقق
to check the state of the owner's rigor mortis!
من حالة تصلّب جثّة المالك غالباً
So what Ayako-san saw was--
...ما رأته أياكو-سان إذاً
Yes. A completely blank test with no answers written at all!
أجل، أوراق اختبار فارغة بلا أيّ إجابة
The reason he didn't write anything down
وسبب عدم حلّه لشيء
was because there would be no point.
هو لأنّه لم يكن هناك مغزى
In other words,
...ما يعني
you knew that the owner wouldn't be grading the tests
أنّك كنت تعرف أنّ المالك لن يصحح الاختبارات
because he was no longer alive!
!بما أنّه لم يعد حيّاً
If you're going to claim this is all nonsense,
إذا كنت ستدّعي أن هذا هراء
then would you kindly show us your test?
فهلّا أريتنا أوراق اختبارك؟
Right now!
!فوراً
D-Damn it!
!تـ-تبّاً
Why, you...
...أيّها الوغد
Speak up! Why did you want me and the owner dead?!
!تكلّم! لمَ أردت قتلي والمالك؟
"The Disparagement of Irene Adler."
"سخرية آيرين أدلر"
His motive was most likely the book you helped the owner write.
الدافع كان الكتاب الذي ساعدتَ المالك بنشره غالباً
What?!
مـ-ماذا؟
Irene? The actress who outwitted Holmes in one of the stories?
آيرين؟ الممثلة التي فاقت هولمز ذكاءً في إحدى قصصه؟
Yes. But the owner's book was mostly about
...أجل، لكن كان معظم كتاب المالك
Holmes' failure as a detective.
عن عثرات هولمز كمتحرٍّ
Now I see.
فهمت
Togano-san felt that the book insulted Holmes, so he--
...شعر توغانو أن الكتاب أهان هولمز لذا قرر
Just the opposite.
على النقيض
Irene was the only woman Sherlock admired.
كانت آيرين المرأة الوحيدة التي اعترف بها شارلوك
I couldn't possibly see such a woman ridiculing him.
يستحيل أن أتخيل سخرية مرأة مثلها منه
I couldn't allow it...
...لم أستطع مسامحته
I absolutely couldn't!
!قطعاً
That was incredible, Hattori-kun!
!كنت مذهلاً يا هاتّوري-كن
Just what I'd expect from the great western detective!
!كما يُتوقع من متحرّي الغرب العظيم
Uh oh!
!كلا
But of course!
!بالطبع
A case like this is like a walk in the park for me!
!قضيّة كهذه لقمة سائغة لي
Looks like I made it through this without having my cover blown...
...يبدو أنّني حللت هذا دون أن تُكتشف هويّتي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
I'm right here, Ran!
!أنا هنا يا ران-نيتشان
Hey.
أنت
You're Kudo, aren't you?
إنّك كودو، صحيح؟
What are you talking about? I'm just a kid!
!ما-ما الذي تقوله؟ أنا مجرد طفل! طفل
Your fake Kansai dialect was pathetic!
لكنة كانساي الزائفة خاصتك كان بائسة
Oh! So this is the gizmo you used to imitate my voice!
هذه هي إذاً؟ الأداة التي استعملتها لتقليد صوتي
I saw you using it in the corner of my eye!
رأيتك تستعملها بطرف عيني
At what point?
في أيّ مرحلة؟
"It would become possible."
"سيصبح ذلك في نطاق المعقول"
You talk a little strangely,
اختيارك للكلمات غريب نوعاً ما
but from your tone and the way you set up your theories
لكن من أسلوبك وشرح استنتاجاتك
you're definitely Shinichi Kudo!
!أنت كودو شينتشي بلا شك
What do you mean? Look at me! I'm just a kid!
!ما-ما قصدك؟ أنا مجرّد طفل
Fine, have it your way.
حسناً، كما تشاء
Hey, check this out! You'll never guess!
أعيرين مسامعك! لديّ قصة مسليّة
The truth is--
...في الحقيقة ذاك الـ
Hold on!
!انتظر
and now you're living with your girlfriend
وتعيش مع الفتاة التي تحبّها كي تستطيع إيجاد
She's not my girlfriend. She's a pain in the ass.
لا-لا أحبّها بالتحديد، تلك الفتاة المزعجة
You two sure are getting along well!
يبدو أنّكما على وفاق
Yeah!
!أجل
Hey, wanna hear what Kudo once said about you?
اسمعي، أتريدين معرفة ما قاله كودو عنك قبلاً؟
He said you're so annoying he can't stand you!
!قال أنّك مزعجة جدّاً ولا يطيقك
Annoying?!
مزعجة؟
Jerk!
!يا وغد
That's what you get for putting me to sleep!
هذا جزاؤك لتنويمي
What's this?
!هذا... أثر قطع بشفرة
Someone's trying to kill Hiroshi-kun
حاول أحدهم قتل هيروشي-كن !بجعلها تبدو حوادث عرضيّة
The next episode of Conan is
جريمة قتل الإرسالية الأولى
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Traffic Mirror.
مرآة عبور
Next episode sees the return of a popular series!
!سلسلة ذات شعبيّة كبيرة في الحلقة القامة
The Detective Boys play a huge role!
!دور كبير لفرقة فتيان التحرّي
Again?
من جديد؟